<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lollback Family 2014 Holiday in Japan</title>
    <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lollback Family 2014 Holiday in Japan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://japan2014.lollback.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Twenty - And so it is Christmas, in Japan!!!</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/25/day-twenty-and-so-it-is-christmas-in-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/25/day-twenty-and-so-it-is-christmas-in-japan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Christmas morning arrived and we enjoyed handing out family Christmas cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_08-47-39_IMG_8495.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ Christmas cards&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gift time was fun as we opened many packages with keepsakes from our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_08-53-41_IMG_8496.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Hats&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our breakfast menu was pancakes and maple syrup, not very Japanese but a family favourite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had fun making the Mazda car key rings.  More construction took place as we had entered the land Nano blocks.  James and Jason began making a Shinkansen from the Nano Gauge series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_11-04-43_IMG_8499.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Shinkansen Nano Gauge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer and Kathy started making the cute Hokkaido Dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_11-05-00_IMG_8500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen Hokkaido NanoBlock&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we were having so much fun we almost forgot we were in Kyoto and decided we should fix that and go out and explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our introduction to the Kyoto culture began at The Myseum of Kyoto.  This city played a major role in the development of Japanese life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_17-20-38_IMG_4582.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Museum of Kyoto&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We entered through the annex to the museum which was the former bank of Japan, a very impressive building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside,we walked along a street of shops and restaurants that were based on the traditional Kyoto townhouse design of the late Edo Period.   We found a  video of Chef making pasta by hand, rolling, folding and flouring dough and cutting precisely into tiny 1mm strips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An English tour guide told us about  four periods of history from the 8th to the 20th century- Heian, Kamkura, Muromachi and Edo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this museum we saw a display on the famous Gion festival. These traditions have been passed down and celebrated since the 8th Century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time for some more Christmas spirit. We walked around central Kyoto found a Christmas tree light display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_18-06-08_IMG_4586.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Family Christmas Tree photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally we stumbled across a Chef making Udon Noodles, this time with a modern approach, using a rolling and cutting machine. We watched through the window and then went inside to see menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_18-14-10_IMG_8502.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chef making noodles&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer ordered Kamaage udon (which was noodles that you ate with a dipping sauce] and we ordered Torotama udon (udon noodles with a dipping sauce, grated yam and hot spring egg). There were lots of nice accompaniments that we ordered including Inari (bead curd rice ball), calamari tempura, sweet potato tempura and vegetable kakiage. Everything was delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_19-03-52_IMG_8506.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ eating Udon&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At home we enjoyed a supper of momiji manju cakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-25_20-39-32_IMG_8519.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ CAKES&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🎄Happy Christmas to our family and friends.🎄&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Nineteen - Christmas Eve in Kyoto</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/24/day-nineteen-christmas-eve-in-kyoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/24/day-nineteen-christmas-eve-in-kyoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now we were settled in Kyoto, we needed a Christmas tree, so James and Jennifer assembled and decorated our traveling tree. We unpacked our origami Santas and hooray, we were ready for Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/IMG_8489.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Christmas tree&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an apartment in the best location, just around the corner from Teramachi-dori street and the Nishiki Food Market. Woo Hoo!!! So we just had to explore&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was seafood galore, alive and fillets. Fresh fruits and vegetables in abundance.  Lots of pickles. Delicacies of all imaginable and unimaginable kinds.  Kathy tried pickled radish, which was unusual but ok.  We bought some vegetables including purple skinned potato which we&amp;rsquo;d seen done tempura style in Tokyo but we wondered what it would be liked mashed.  We loved the handicrafts and there were many and they were beautiful.  We were like children in a candy store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/DSC01820.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;market photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found these Christmas dress ups and had to try them out, it was Christmas Eve after all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/DSC01816.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Family Santa hat photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Eighteen - Zoom, Zoom, the Boys trip to the Mazda Museum</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/23/day-eighteen-zoom-zoom-the-boys-trip-to-the-mazda-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 22:15:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/23/day-eighteen-zoom-zoom-the-boys-trip-to-the-mazda-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the boys went to the Mazda Museum and factory tour at Mazda&amp;rsquo;s headquarters in Hiroshima, starting with an early train from Hiroshima Station to Mukainada Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short walk we arrived at Mazda&amp;rsquo;s Japanese Headquarters, where we were greeted and invited to view both classic and new models on display or play in the games room while waiting for the tour to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James took a particular liking to the sporty lines of the Roadster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-DSC01753.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;james and roadster 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_4497.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James standing with roadster&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the games room we were able to race some some Mazdas on a simulator and have our photo taken in the photo booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_4500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;james driving simulator&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-5498be3b022c2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boys in photo booth&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right on schedule the bus arrived to take us from the office to the Mazda Museum.  The plant sprawls along 7km on both sides of the Enko river.  The worlds largest private bridge was built by Mazda to provide access to both sides of the plant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way we pass Mazda&amp;rsquo;s private coal/steam electricity plant, the water treatment and recycling plant and on-site accomodation for single workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrive at the museum we&amp;rsquo;re shown an introductory video, that demonstrates just how significant Mazda is in Hiroshima.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the video, the tour of the museum begins and we get to see some of the first Madza&amp;rsquo;s ever produced - and they weren&amp;rsquo;t cars!  The first Mazda&amp;rsquo;s were three wheeled bikes and trucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_4514.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;3 wheel bikes and trucks&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking pride of place was the Mazda 787B that won LeMans in 1991 and our guide proudly pointed out that Mazda are the only Japanese car manufacturer to have won LeMans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-DSC01767.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Picture of Mazda 787&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next it was time to view the engine section of the museum, where there were an assortment of Mazda enginges on display, with a special focus on the Rotary engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-DSC01778.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cutout of rotary engine&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour includes displays showing how cars progress through the assembly line, including the panelling, painting and assembly stages of the production line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-DSC01789.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Car chassis&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour then takes weaves its way onto an elevated gangtry above the live assembly line where we were able to see the final assembly stages of production.  Unfortunately we weren&amp;rsquo;t able to take pictures in the plant area but it was fascinating to see an RX8 followed by a CX5 being assembled on the same line together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving the production and assembly area we exit to a gallery with Mazda protoype vehicles that have been displayed at international Motor Shows.  There were Hybrid test vehicles and even a Hydrogen powered rotary engine on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-DSC01806.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Future car&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we leave the museum we get a fantasic view of the private port, where between 4000 and 6000 Mazda&amp;rsquo;s are loaded onto international cargo ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then returned back to the office passing the design centre, where new models are drawn, designed and modelled out of clay and plastic as a part of the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the tour we made our way back to the train station and headed back into the city to rejoin the girls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Eighteen - Girls garden at Shukkein</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/23/day-eighteen-girls-garden-at-shukkein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/23/day-eighteen-girls-garden-at-shukkein/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girls found peace in the most beautiful and tranquil miniature garden they have ever seen, Shukkein.  It&amp;rsquo;s name literally means &amp;ldquo;shrink-scenery garden&amp;rdquo;, which is very apt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the centre of the garden is Takuei pond.  One of the stone miniature bridges calling us to cross.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen bridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun feeding the coi, some were very large!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8127.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coi feeding&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We delighted in seeing the miniature gardens which represented various scenic views across Japan, for example a remote mountain and solitary valley and a broad sea shore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8141.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JK selfie&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked the Koko-kyo bridge which spanned the centre of the pond. Its name means straddling rainbow bridge. We fed the coi again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8156-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coi&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were so many beautiful views in this garden, we found it hard to decide our favourite. We did rather fancied this quaint red bridge over the pond.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8157.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen on red bridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were fortunate enough to have visitors in the gardens today. A traditional Japanese couple came to visit in honour of the Emporer&amp;rsquo;s birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8163.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kimono lady &amp;amp; Traditional male&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden was destroyed by fire in the atomic bombing in 1945 but it has been restored to its condition prior to the bombing.We can highly recommend a visit to these beautiful gardens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls then ventured through the Hiroshima Prefectural Art Museum.  Would you believe the first exhibit we saw was a polished timber Mazda! We thought the boys would love this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8167.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mazda&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the exhibition halls there were three artists featured from Hiroshima who were born in the latter half of the Meiji period, the sculptor Katsuzo Entsuba, a western art painter, Sho Yamaji and a Japanese style painter Setsuji Wadaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked some oil paintings by Mr Sho Yamaji. Our favourite was Roses by Masao Haitani &amp;amp; Sho Yamaji. We laughed when we saw another exhibit by Sho Yamaji titled &amp;ldquo;Still life with a T shaped ruler&amp;rdquo;, we thought James would like that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found that Setsuji Wadaka,  used the technique colour on paper to produce works such as Fireman in the Village, Woman selling Fish and Village Children. We liked the Woman at the Ravine where both a sketch and painting were displayed.It showed how his initial idea transformed into the final piece of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next artwork we really liked was done by Genso Okuda who put colour on silk. We particularly liked &amp;ldquo;Waiting for the Moon&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Autumn Forest and the Moon&amp;rdquo;, they were stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our journey to Kyoto was nearing, so we left the Museum to meet the boys at the Hiroshima station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We caught the Shinkansen Sakura 552 to Shin-Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8202.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shinkansen to Shin-Osaka&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very short trip on the Shinkansen Kodama 670 to Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-23-IMG_8206.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;inside Shinkansen Kodama Jason &amp;amp; J&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Kyoto station and it truly felt like a maze, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a way out without lots of stairs. So, if you can&amp;rsquo;t get through the mountain, go around the mountain. We walked outside and around to the front. Possibly the only travellers to have ever done this but it worked for us. We collected the key to our apartment and set off towards our new abode for the next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We easily found the apartment and the weary travellers enjoyed a cup of tea or hot chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Seventeen - Magnificent Miyajima</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/22/day-seventeen-magnificent-miyajima/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/22/day-seventeen-magnificent-miyajima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow! It was a lovely surprise to walk outside our hotel and find that it was snowing. A big smile filled our faces as a little magic felt like it had been added to our day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We caught the bus to Hiroshima station to catch the JR Sanyo line to Miyajimaguchi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_11-13-17_IMG_8063.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Train Sanyo line &#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Miyajimaguchi.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_11-48-45_IMG_8065.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sign&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only a couple of minutes walk to the Miyajima Ferry Port where we caught the ferry to Miyajima Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our ferry arrived and we were excited to board. This was James&amp;rsquo; first ferry ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_12-04-13_IMG_4380.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ferry&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_12-22-24_IMG_4393.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;full size ferry&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the island, we were greeted by deer who were quite tame but wanted to eat paper, like our brochures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_12-43-30_IMG_4403.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;deer photo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_13-25-10_IMG_4446.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James and Jennifer with deer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way through the Omotesando shopping arcade, we saw some lovely crafts.  We bought some of the famous momiji manju, maple leaf shaped cakes for a lunch treat. They come in many flavours, we chose custard cream and chocolate. With treats in hand, we walked past the O-tori Gate while the tide was still high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_13-17-28_DSC01722.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen and James with Gate at high tide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then headed up to the Five-storied pagoda, said to have been built in 1407, is 28 metres high and is a combination of Japanese and Chinese styles of architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_13-28-32_DSC01726.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;5 Story pagoda&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view back to Mijayaguchi was lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_13-57-36_DSC01728.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;view from island&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked along the edge of the island towards the O-tori Gate and Itsukushima Shrine, we commented that Mijayama was very beautiful and peaceful.  We enjoyed a lovely walk to the Daiganji Temple and Kiyomori Shrine, through the quaint streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_14-28-25_IMG_4463.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;picture on bridge&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off towards Momijidani Park, parts of which were bush walking. It felt reminiscent of the Bunya Mountains.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_14-48-47_IMG_8089.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Momijidani park&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to do some shopping at a craft shop and the rope way looked scary for some, so we decided to head back.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_15-10-10_IMG_8104.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jennifer and new hat&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we approached the Itsukushima Shrine, we noticed the tide had gone out completely and we could walk out to O-torii gate. How special!!
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_15-48-10_DSC01729.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ O-torii gate&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_15-59-58_IMG_4473.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ O-torii gate&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss of us not to stock up on momiji manju cakes, as they were oishii!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_16-11-40_IMG_4478.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jennifer and Momihi Manju cake&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A return journey on the ferry and JR Sanyo line took us back to Hiroshima.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_17-00-08_IMG_8114.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JR Sanyo train&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner we decided to try Okonimiyaki, so we found a restaurant where we could watch them being made. It was truly captivating, not a peep from anyone, not even our story teller, James.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of the Hiroshima style &amp;lsquo;Okonomimur-yaki&amp;rsquo; is said to be, that soon after the 2nd World War, people mixed flour provided by the U.S. Army with water, thinly spread it on a hot plate and sprinkled it with chopped spring onion. Now they add cabbage, bean sprouts, buckwheat, noodles, pork and egg. We all ordered the traditional one, three of us with Udon noodles and Jennifer ordered hers with Chinese noodles. Oishii!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_18-08-58_IMG_4484.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Okonomimur-yaki being cooked&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2015/01/2014-12-22_18-16-34_DSC01748.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Okonomimur-yaki being served&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Sixteen - Science Fun at the Hiroshima Children&#39;s Museum</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/21/day-sixteen-science-fun-at-the-hiroshima-childrens-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/21/day-sixteen-science-fun-at-the-hiroshima-childrens-museum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today we decided to visit the Hiroshima Children&amp;rsquo;s Museum.  The first activity we spied was a ball maze. We had great fun winding balls onto the run at different locations and watching them complete the track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_10-52-17_IMG_7990.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ball maze&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jen enjoyed making electricity by picking up a ball with a control panel and dropping it through a basketball hoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_10-55-48_IMG_7997-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen basketball&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr White would be proud of Jennifer and James making circuits with bulbs and batteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_11-10-19_IMG_8002-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;battery circuits&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time for a sprint so we tested how fast can the Lollback&amp;rsquo;s could run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/cs4MMJyCKP4?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13.92km/hr Kathy
14.72 km/hr James
15.41 km/hr Jen
18.00 km/hr Jason&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racing the cars with solar power was awesome! You had to maintain the solar light on your race car for it to have enough solar power to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_12-39-44_IMG_8008.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Solar picture&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It even had solar panels on helicopters whose rotors spun when given solar energy and animals that moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/wGcmfZPOgZo?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model train track with Shinkansen and trams was a lot of fun. The A700 Shinkansen was fitted with a camera so you could watch the view from the driver&amp;rsquo;s seat.  We enjoyed driving the various modes of transport around the rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_13-01-06_IMG_8021.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;train track picture&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We launched a rocket into space and attempted to land at our assigned mission location. Some attempts were successful, others were not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we boarded the Street Car tram and headed to the Hiroshima Port. It was rather cold and windy but we we saw some big boats and would you believe they had markets here!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_14-39-07_IMG_8034.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little shopping on the way home kept us entertained especially since there was a market fair day and we were able to taste test some yoghurt, cheese, milk, donut, cream bun and juice. James thought it was especially great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered a smorgasbord of dishes for dinner to try some new dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-21_18-12-04_IMG_8037.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Smorgasbord&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Fifteen - Hiroshima, International city of World Peace &amp; the Castle Town</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/20/day-fifteen-international-city-of-world-peace-the-castle-town-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/20/day-fifteen-international-city-of-world-peace-the-castle-town-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day Fifteen - International city of World Peace &amp;amp; the Castle Town, Hiroshima&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_10-35-04_IMG_4270.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hiroshima Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Terumoto built a castle in Hiroshima as he felt the location was a good hub for river and sea trade and it was important to control the mouth of the river for the city&amp;rsquo;s success and rule over the Chugoku region.  The Hiroshima Castle was constructed 1589, it is an early flatland castle (Hirajiro). The Ota river was used as a natural moat to ferry stones from the inland sea for use to build the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labour required to build the Castles in Japan amazes us and the detail, such as that on the end of roof tiles, is impressive. The ornamental roofing tile is laced with gold.   At Hiroshima Castle, the ends of the ridgepole are decorated with Shachi, which are fabulous fish shaped ornaments.  We thought this was rather appropriate for a castle surrounded by sea/river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dressed up and pretended we were Samaurai protecting the Castle and also dressed up rather fancy in a Kimono.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_11-24-07_IMG_7926.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Samuari photo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_11-46-21_IMG_4271.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kimono&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local area grew plants that were not affected by salt water such as sweet potato, figs, locus flower and spring onion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked upon the small Samuari homes. They were neat with their tatami mats and all in one kitchen storage box/table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of swords on display, but no photos could be taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 5th floor gave us a view of Hiroshima. We even looked back across to our hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_12-29-18_IMG_7943.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from Hiroshima Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked towards the A-Dome we stopped to watch a Christmas concert by the Hiroshima Boys Chorus Choir.  They sang songs we recognised such as Joy to the World, Jingle Bells, Rudolph the Red Nose reindeer and We wish you a Merry Christmas.  Our favourite was Rudolph the Red Nose reindeer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/uEKKJPFr_sM?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/HTw29MlA18k?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re beginning to feel like it&amp;rsquo;s Christmas!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next visit was very humbling. We reflected upon the damage left by the Atomic bomb on August 6, 1945 at the Genbaku Dome-Mae (Atomic Bomb Dome).We could see the building was severely damaged and burnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we found the Children&amp;rsquo;s Peace Monument. There is a story attached to the construction of this monument. A young girl was injured as a result of the atomic bomb but lived only to find out when she was 10 years old that she had leukaemia. She believed that if she madder 1000 origami paper cranes she would survive the illness but unfortunately about a year later she passed away.Children from her school wanted to honour her and other children who lost their lives as a result of the atomic bomb by making the remaining cranes and establishing the Children&amp;rsquo;s Peace Monument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pond of peace was serene with the flame of peace which will remain lit until there are no more atomic bombs in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_14-23-01_IMG_7955.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Flame of Peace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We entered the Hiroshima Peace Memorial Museum. The realisation of the devastation brought tears, described as a nightmare that came true. We continued to read stories of loss, searching for loved ones and how it all unfolded, all of which pulled at the heart strings and left us pondering why this was necessary. Was it the only way to stop the war? Was it really used as a data collection/training exercise? How could such a traumatic and painful action that affected thousands of lives be justified?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Peace Memorial Museum certainly conveyed the horror of nuclear weapons and desire for world peace.We hope that world peace is achieved too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When choosing what to do for dinner tonight we decided to look for a place that had a queue as we figured it must be good.  Ordering was so easy as inside the door was a machine which displayed all the menu items in English and allowed you to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_19-48-43_IMG_4289.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Interactive menu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James and Jennifer enjoyed making their own selection and feeding the money into the machine.  We enjoyed a scrumptious dinner of soup and pork cutlets on rice with a Japanese sauce that you poured over the top and James enjoyed Chicken and prawn cutlets with rice and soup.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_18-49-45_IMG_7967.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dinner&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst we were having dinner a Christmas tram passed by the window, it looked great with lights and Santa on board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-20_18-43-04_IMG_4288.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Christmas Tram&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Fourteen - Bound for Hiroshima</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/19/day-fourteen-bound-for-hiroshima/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/19/day-fourteen-bound-for-hiroshima/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We made our way on the Osaka Loop line and Rapid Train to Shin-Osaka, you see James can&amp;rsquo;t get enough train rides! At Shin-Osaka we we caught the Shinkansen Sakura 553 to Hiroshima. It was rather luxurious and a most enjoyable train ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-19_10-55-53_IMG_7911.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James Shinkansen Sakura&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the Rhinga Royal hotel in Hiroshima and was excited to find we had a room on the 24th floor with a view of the Hiroshima Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-19_13-57-13_IMG_7914.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from Hotel window&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to hop on the loop bus to do a tour of Hiroshima.  We caught our first glimpse of the Peace Museum, saw many street cars (trams), in fact James counted around 30 and a different view of the Hiroshima Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Thirteen- Tennoji (Osaka) Zoo and Tsutenkaku</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/18/day-thirteen-tennoji-osaka-zoo-and-tsutenkaku/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/18/day-thirteen-tennoji-osaka-zoo-and-tsutenkaku/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We zipped out to Tennoji today.  First of all we visited Shitennoji temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_11-56-36_DSC01528.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ Shitennoji temple&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Off to the zoo we go&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought the ducks were quite pretty, well for ducks, with their orange colouring. Orange is one of James&amp;rsquo; favourite colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-11-23_DSC01529.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ducks&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a trainer who was showing off his Noma Pony. It was so cute we gave him a pat and a hug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-17-57_IMG_7842.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ pony&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black bear was pacing his enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-20-58_IMG_7846.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ black Bear&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James and Jennifer liked the Polar bear because we actually got to see him. Many times at SeaWorld the Polar Bear was out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-24-14_IMG_7847.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Polar Bear&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought this Great Gray Owl was aptly named.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-26-56_IMG_7851.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Owl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped for a little snack by this cute little Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heidi, Heidi Ho, the great big elephant so slow. This one was a big beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_13-44-05_IMG_7856.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Asian elephant&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lemurs and monkeys were very entertaining and cheeky. The babies seemed shy at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fancy seeing an Emu in Japan.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_14-15-13_DSC01540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James &amp;amp; Emu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James and Jennifer struck a friendship with this long eared goat. We think he wanted something to eat, he ate someone&amp;rsquo;s brochure.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_14-18-29_DSC01546.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Goat&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Penguins were cute too and none appeared to want to escape. They were having fun sliding around and lining up on parade for us.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_14-25-53_IMG_7858.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Penguins&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought the Tiger looked at the ready prowling around his enclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-00-58_DSC01564.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tiger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our junior lions were in training to see the Lion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-09-11_IMG_7862.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ &amp;amp; Lion statue&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We loved the regal Lion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-12-33_IMG_7867.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second to the Lion, Kathy was pleased to see the graceful Giraffe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-16-50_DSC01569.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Giraffe&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another statue, this time a Hippopotamus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-26-47_DSC01574.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hippopotamus&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean (red) flamingoes were beautiful, a much deeper pink than the Lesser Flamingoes .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-29-54_DSC01576.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carribean red flamingoes&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Zoo we set off in search of the Billiken-San near the Tsutenkaku, a tip from our friend Saori. The Biliken-San is a gold smiling statue which looks like the Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a huge paper fish lantern and look what was behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_15-48-16_IMG_4257.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJK Fish Lantern&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to investigate but we weren&amp;rsquo;t sure if it was the right one as the Saori had told us it was near the Tsutenkaku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see the Tsutenkaku in the distance so we walked up to it. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one so we went into the Tower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learn some interesting facts about the tower. The lights on top indicate the next day&amp;rsquo;s weather forecast. We saw Orange on top of white lights which means cloudy/clear weather for tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clock on the side of the Tower
is the biggest in Japan. Its face is 5.5 metres across and the minute hand is 3.2 metres long and weighs 25kg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also 6 LED patterns with a different colour which represents different seasons:
White - Snow - Jan &amp;amp; Feb
Pink - Cherry Blossoms- Mar &amp;amp; Apr
Green - New Leaves - May &amp;amp; June
Blue - Sea/Sky - Jul &amp;amp; Aug
Gold - Ears of rice - Sept~Nov
Blue-Green - Fir tree - Dec&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside we caught an elevator to the second floor which opened to a floor which looked like we were inside a tram car. It was an early 1900&amp;rsquo;s Hankai tramway from when the tower opened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then went to the observation tower and found the eight deities of good fortune. James and Jennifer collected the stamps from each one. James liked the Ebisu as he was holding a fish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_16-38-42_IMG_7883.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James Ebisu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jennifer liked Jurojin who was holding a deer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_16-32-32_IMG_7874.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen Jurojin&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you pat the Billiken&amp;rsquo;s foot you will have good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view from inside across Osaka was very nice.  The sun was almost setting which added something special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_16-59-32_DSC01597.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ heads through poster&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went outside and saw the tower lit up in Blue-Green, the colour for the Fir tree in December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_17-08-26_IMG_7896.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tower with lights&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home we saw a Christmas light display. They have some beautiful light displays in Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_17-29-07_DSC01607.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Christmas tree&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought this Santa made out of poinsettia flowers at Tennoji station was rather adorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-18_17-33-24_IMG_7908.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Santa flowers&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked past a butcher selling marinated cooked pork, so stopped for a taste. It was so delicious we bought one for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Twelve - Osaka History</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/17/day-twelve-osaka-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/17/day-twelve-osaka-history/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our day started at the Osaka Museum of History.  If you ever get the chance to visit Osaka, we highly recommend this museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our history lesson on the 10th floor, where we saw a partial reconstruction of the Daigokuden (the main palace building) of the Nara period of Naniwa Palace. We saw many mannequins dressed in period court dress and life size replicas of the 70 cm pillars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_10-40-25_IMG_7797-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mannequin Jennifer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the observation area we looked across to the remains of this former site, but it was pleasing to see it has been cared for, so the story lives on today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we learnt about the Hongan-ji   temple. It was an unsettling period (Edo Period) of fighting with Lord Oda Nobunaga. We really enjoyed seeing lots of miniature models (1/20th scale) of the townspeople in Naniwa.  This model is a reconstruction of the latter Naniwa Palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_10-50-28_IMG_7798-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reconstruction of the latter Naniwa Palace&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked this medieval street in Sakai in 1568. In particular the stones that held the roof on, which was similar to the Samaurai house we saw in Matsumoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_10-56-43_IMG_7800-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Model of Medieval Street&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Temma Fruit and Vegetable Market was cool with displays of all the different produce. This Market was built primarily for the distribution of produce from farms and villages surrounding Osaka. Apparently all prices were set by this Market which caused some conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-02-41_IMG_7803-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Temma market&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked this model of the township of Temba from 1854-1860, in the area near Yodobashi. The detail of the miniature models was quite extraordinary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-08-19_IMG_7806-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Townscape of Temba&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 8th floor we had the best time being archaeologists. We started identifying the real artefact from pieces that had been dug up. The next activity we were given pieces of a vase and had to piece it back together using clues from the markings on the vase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-24-07_IMG_7811-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ vase puzzle&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-30-47_IMG_7812-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ finished vase puzzle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then enjoyed a puzzle putting together the layers of earth underneath Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-39-22_IMG_7814-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen layers of earth puzzle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boys did a puzzle of the layout of the Naniwa Palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_12-00-25_IMG_7819.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Boys old Palace puzzle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The girls did the other puzzle of the Nara period Palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_11-58-55_IMG_7818-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Girls Palace puzzle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James and Jennifer then embarked on an archaeological mapping exercise where they were given a map with some findings and had to search the life sized excavation area to find what had not yet been mapped. They did a rather fine job and were rewarded with certificates from the Tesearch Director, Dr Suko.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_12-12-01_IMG_7821-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJ Archaeology certificate&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the next level down we played a quiz style game called &amp;ldquo;Sugoroku&amp;rdquo;, it was a lot of fun and we learnt a little more history about Osaka/Japanese history.  To play we each chose a counter and rolled the dice.  The board was designed in a spiral fashion, we started on the outside edge and the winner was the first to the centre of the board, the Castle.  Some spaces had questions, if you answered it correctly you moved forward 3 spaces, if it was incorrect you moved back one space.  With a little assistance from our tutor  (some &amp;ldquo;hinto&amp;rdquo; as he called it) and some picture clues we did ok and had a great time while doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_12-49-53_IMG_7823-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;board game photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a copy of the questions so we may try some out on friends when we get home, but here&amp;rsquo;s one for now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five-storied pagoda at Shittenno-ji Temple, this temple has a very big torii (gate of shinto shrine) at the West gate.
Torii is made of ________?
1⃣stone
2⃣wood
3⃣iron&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked across the road to the Castle and we&amp;rsquo;re not sure what happened but the wind was absolutely freezing and blowing strongly, we hereafter referred to it as the snow winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan has vending machines everywhere and we mean everywhere, outside the front of buildings along the street, throughout parks and train stations, just to name a few spots. As we walked through Osaka Castle park and the snow winds were racing through us, we decided to try one of these machines that dispense cans of cold and hot drinks. Today hot chocolates were on the menu. It really was hot and  tasted quite good. We can&amp;rsquo;t believe it only cost 130 yen (~$1.30)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_13-37-03_IMG_4227-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James vending machine&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked through the gate and noticed the enormous stones in the wall and wondered how on earth they built the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_16-28-22_IMG_4238-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJK stone wall&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out it is a mystery to the Osaka people as well, as there is no information which documents this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed watching some short films about Hideyoshi Toyotomi and the Castle. Hideyoshi built the Castle in 1583. After his death the political control moved to the Tokugawas and the castle fell during the Summer War in 1615.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tokugawa Shogunate reconstructed the Osaka Castle in 1620 and it took 10 years to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;War, weather and fires seemed to play havoc with the Castle, as another incident, a lightning strike destroyed the Main Tower in 1665.  Fires affected many buildings during the troublesome transition to Imperial restoration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked the Gold Lion which guards the front wall of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_16-03-52_IMG_4231-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;KJJ gold Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series of slide shows that explained the life of Hideyoshi Toyotomi from birth to building the Osaka Castle and his achievement in unifying the entire nation was really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The view from the top of the Castle across the city was terrific.  It was however a very quick lap around the perimeter, as the wind was so strong it was blowing us against the Castle in places, not to mention it was freezing cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_14-07-07_IMG_4228-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from Osaka Castle roof&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked out of the Castle the wind blew us against the handrail. We had enjoyed learning about the history of Osaka Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_16-24-08_IMG_4236-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;JJJ front of Osaka Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was Umeda as we had heard about a great underground shopping centre, perfect for being out of the wind.  We found a market style floor of food shops and enjoyed tasting treats. We really liked these purple/black beans sweet treats. Jennifer has loved the bean curd rice rolls and we found a stand that had different flavoured rice fillings. We bought some with rice, mushroom and sesame seeds, they were very nice indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_18-47-45_IMG_7824-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen eating rice roll&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought some other yummy foods to try and asked if there was anywhere to sit. The Japanese games that Mr Mackenzie Smith teaches came in handy again as Jennifer and James remembered that &amp;ldquo;Suwatte kudasai&amp;rdquo; means to sit please and we were shown the way.  The custard Danish (not so Japanese though)!were sensational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-17_18-54-28_IMG_7826-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James eating danish&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another new little treat we tried today was called Genjie pie. It is a crunchy light texture, heart shaped pastry which is backed with chocolate, which comes individually wrapped. The packaging says, &amp;ldquo;Why don&amp;rsquo;t you make your tea time happier with Genji? Heart Warming Pie&amp;rdquo;.  We did and we were pleased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked home we noticed it was 2 degrees celsius!  We&amp;rsquo;ve seen lower temperatures but with the snowy winds it was undoubtedly the coldest we had felt so far on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer to Sugoroku quiz = 1⃣stone
Hope you were right!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Eleven - Osaka Aquarium Kaiyukan</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/16/day-eleven-osaka-aquarium-kaiyukan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 22:06:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/16/day-eleven-osaka-aquarium-kaiyukan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our first rainy day plan had to be enacted today which set us off to the port in Osaka to see the biggest aquarium in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the entire day here as we all love animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After walking through a big dome tank we found the adorable otters.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7730.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James Jen Otters&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seals were entertaining and we enjoyed watching their feeding presentation.  All the trainers came out dressed like Santa&amp;rsquo;s helpers. The seals performed great tricks, waving, turning, making a fan, sliding into the water and jumping out.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7732.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Trainer Seal&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The capybara were cute. They are the largest rodent, have webbed feet and two very large front teeth.  James and Jennifer learnt about these animals on the tv show called &amp;ldquo;Scope&amp;rdquo;. We went back to watch him get fed and saw him enjoy Pak Choy and carrots.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7742-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Trainer Capybara&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We liked watching the sea lions.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7745.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jen James sea Lion&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dolphins are always a favourite, so clever and graceful. We went back to watch the feeding presentation and the Dolphins put on a great show.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7762-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Trainer and Dolphin&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We watched the King Island penguins and we are always are bewildered how they fit such big fish into their beaks.  We always enjoy watching their waddle, they are very cute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We watched the feeding in the shark tank. Many of the small fish (food) fell to the tank floor and it was fascinating to watch the stingray flap to make a wave and lift the fish enough to scoop them up in their mouths. They did a great job cleaning up the fish off the sea floor. In fact they probably got more fish than the Sharks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sloth was living up to his name, hanging about on a tree limb until a trainer with some food came his way.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-DSC01508.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sloth &amp;amp; Jen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were highly amused by the Hopper penguins.  There was one who appeared to be trying to escape down the drain. He stood in the drain when the cleaner took the grate off and he was trying to move the grate with his beak to put himself in there, instead of being in the pen. Another penguin then joined the crusade and we imagined the fish in the tank from Nemo trying to escape down the drain but similarly the penguins quest failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/js3gOj8mFVY?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the lights were beautiful. A huge whale was depicted in coloured lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-DSC01522.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Osaka Aquarium penguin lights with Jen &amp;amp; James&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Ten - Hakuba to Osaka</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/15/day-ten-hakuba-to-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/15/day-ten-hakuba-to-osaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With twinges of sadness, but wonderful memories we left the beautiful Hakuba village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-15-IMG_4095-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Snowman Village&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob kindly drove us to Hakuba Station and James and Jennifer collected their town stamp.  Our train soon arrived so we farewelled Hakuba and started our journey towards Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-15-IMG_7709-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Train at Hakuba&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We quickly disembarked at what we thought was Matsumoto, we were ready for the rush of a 3 minute changeover to catch the Nagoya train. One problem, we didn&amp;rsquo;t jump off at Matsumoto, we were one station early. Fortunately the Train Guard stopped us and we got back on the train.  We explained to the Guard we were in a rush and had &amp;ldquo;san&amp;rdquo; (3) minutes to catch our train to Nagoya.  The next stop we were ready!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evidence of how thoughtful, considerate and helpful the Japanese people are was about to be displayed&amp;hellip; The Guard confirmed we needed to go to platform 1. We dashed towards the lifts, the people in the lift tried to fit us in but the doors would not shut even with only 3 in the lift, so we hopped out to wait off the next one. The lift doors opened again, we jumped in and at the top another Guard was waiting who told us they were holding the train for us and showed us to the platform.  Another Guard was at the bottom of the escalators who directed us to hop on the train. Phew! With all that help we made it and were bound for Nagoya on the Shannon 10 Limited Express train. Arigato Matsumoto!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-15-IMG_7715-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shinano 10 Limited Express&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick changeover in Nagoya we were on James&amp;rsquo; favourite train the Shinkansen Hikari to Osaka.  This train sped along like a rocket yet was very smooth. We all agreed it was the best train ride so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-15-IMG_7721.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shinkansen Hikari James Jen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at Shin-Osaka and swapped to the local express train to go to Osaka station, then hopped on the Osaka Loop line to our local station Morinomiya. We hopped off the train and in a short distance we saw the beautiful and majestic Osaka Castle and felt welcomed to Osaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-15-DSC01444.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo in front of Osaka Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Nine - Hakuba Highlights</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/14/day-nine-hakuba-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/14/day-nine-hakuba-highlights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another magical morning in Hakuba as we awoke to find the incredible snowfall this village experiences.  Apparently it can snow these beautiful fluffy flakes for two weeks straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7678.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;View from window&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We marvelled at the variety of snow machines that came out this morning.  We saw enormous machines designed to clear the roads, small motorised ones to clear a path around houses and one that the driver sits in and drives about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_4065.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Snow machine photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_4055.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow machine photo2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_4076.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow machine photo3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just had to go out and play! We were just continually amazed at how light and fluffy a huge handful of snow was. Equally it was amazing and impressive when it went splat on someone, like a huge powder puff!  Needless to say snowballs were flying everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More snow angel fun was to be had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7686.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow Angel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a huge mound to slide down so couldn&amp;rsquo;t waste that opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/yJMn_EEwChc?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7688.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow slide&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found that some children had made snowmen in front of the Hakuba Ski Condo where we were staying, so we joined in the fun. Three more snowmen were added to the village:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Princess Snowmania created by Jennifer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7699.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jens snowman&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frosty created by Jason:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7697.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jason&#39;s snowman&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr Australia created by James:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7702.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James&#39; snowman&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hours of snow fun, it was time for hot chocolates all round.  We reminisced about the fun we&amp;rsquo;ve had in Hakuba and know we will have wonderful lifetime memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We seem to stumble across lots of interesting things, we found this interesting creation in the garden. We have seen a few variations from the train in home gardens and thought it was a clever way to reuse, recycle and reimagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-14-IMG_7685.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Garden scarecrow contraption&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Eight - Snow Train to Magical Matsumoto</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/13/day-eight-snow-train-to-magical-matsumoto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/13/day-eight-snow-train-to-magical-matsumoto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An early morning rise was necessary today to catch the 7:46 train from Hakuba to Matsumoto. We awoke to find a huge carpet of snow which had completely covered the roads, roofs, cars and trees in the thickest layer of snow we have seen since we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a delight to walk through the sprinkling, soft, powdery snow to Hakuba station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_4024-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Walk to Hakuba Station&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was delayed about 14 minutes due to the heavy snowfall.  We noticed that the train tracks were filled with snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_4035.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Hakuba Station photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought the train might have to travel slower due to the snow but we were wrong, it certainly zoomed along.  Along the way to Shinano-Omachi we noticed the beauty of the overnight snowfall. Fields of snow, houses and trees all covered in snow were all before us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7615-3.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;View from Train&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We changed trains at Shinano-Omachi for the second part of our journey to Matsumoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited the Tourist office and picked up a Town walking map. We decided to visit the Timepiece Museum first but as hard as we tried we just could not find it, so we set off to the Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way we stopped at the Daimyocho Otemon Ido well.  We scooped some pure spring water and enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7624-2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;James Jennifer at well&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the stunning Matsumoto Castle and a kind Japanese man offered to take our photo. We could tell he was very proud of the Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-16-IMG_7626.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Family Matsumoto Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Matsumoto Castle was built in 1593-1594 and is Japan&amp;rsquo;s oldest existing castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside the castle we were greeted by a Samurai and a Japanese lady dressed in a kimono.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7630-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;James Jennifer Samurai Japanese Lady&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the Castle we saw how the Samurai protected the Castle.  Specially shaped rectangular holes were carved to allow the bows and arrows to be at the ready and square carved holes were used for muskets. We also saw where boulders could be dropped down should an intruder try to climb the walls of the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7632.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Inside Castle Jen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed lunch and a hot cup of creamy chocolate / tea at the Castle, it was -1 degree Celsius!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_4043-2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Outside Matsumoto Castle&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was the Former Kaichi School. It was the oldest elementary school in Japan and was founded in 1873.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learnt the name Kaichi means leading a virtuous life and cultivating wisdom. James and Jennifer enjoyed pretending to be students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7635-1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Classroom James&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7636-2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Classroom Jason Jen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought the book work was neat.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7643-1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;maths book&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looked like the textbook pages were printed by rolling over a stencil.
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7645.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Textbook&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7649.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Storybook&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found some very old carvings decorating some doors. This Sankarado has a marvellous wave and dragon sculpture carving which is very special because it is the oldest in existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7651-1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;James Door&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the wall is the motto for school discipline and on display is the school flag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7657-1.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Jennifer motto flag&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We particularly liked this artwork of the top of the Kaichi School building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7660.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Painting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought it was interesting that the school was used as an elementary school, junior high school, woman&amp;rsquo;s school, a technical college for teachers and a facility for social education. It was functional for 90 years until March 1963.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7662.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Outside photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our last stop for the day was the Takahashi Family residence. This is one of the oldest existing samurai residences in the Nagano prefecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7665.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Samurai house photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a fabulous day in Matsumoto, we returned home to Hakuba. We noticed the snow cover had crept much closer to Matsumoto indicating a there will be lots of snow at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were right! The playground of snow in the train station car park was irresistible and had to be enjoyed. Needless to say we played all the way home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-13-IMG_7669.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Hakuba Station Snow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying meiji chocolates on our travels around Japan and today we made the connection that Meiji is a period of time in Japanese history from c.1868 . Oishii!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Seven - Happy at Happo</title>
      <link>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/12/day-seven-happy-at-happo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 22:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://japan2014.lollback.com/2014/12/12/day-seven-happy-at-happo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we woke up this morning it was snowing. Hooray!!  There is something extraordinarily peaceful about watching snow flakes fall, we the novice to snow, could do it for hours, second only to playing in the snow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of snow resorts here in Hakuba. Today we thought we would visit Happo.  We caught the bus from the train station to the ski resort. We were told that Nakiyama would be a good place to go, so we bought a snow board and made our way over to there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;James and Jennifer had enormous fun sliding the slopes, forwards, backwards and sideways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-DSC00142.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Snowboarding Jennifer&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7584.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Snowboarding James&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think Jennifer has waited all her life to do a real snow angel. She&amp;rsquo;s tried it in the Kindergarten sandpit, at the beach and now was her opportunity to do it for real in the snow.  Of course she loved it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7585.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow Angel Jennifer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course not to be out done by his sister, James gave it a try too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7612.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snow Prince James&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was time for making a snowman. Jason created his fun masterpiece, decked out with natural features. Who says he&amp;rsquo;s not creative?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7596.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Snowman built by Jason&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the snowman sneezed?, well something drastic happened and his head fell off!!!! Poor snowman!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7601.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Headless Snowman&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathy built a snow girl and named her Sally SnowGirl. It&amp;rsquo;s our first attempt ever at building snow people and we are truly big kids at heart because it was great fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7606.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;SnowGirl built by Kathy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst this was happening, James and Jennifer starting building an igloo. The igloo was to protect us from the cold and could be a haven for eating, hence a humble abode was in the making. Snow was carried, pulled and thrown (or perhaps that was just a snowball game in between), from all directions. All hands were called to task as stability was difficult at times, but a fine family masterpiece was eventually created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-IMG_7610.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Family Igloo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to sneak further up the mountain to take a look at the gorgeous view. It is exquisite and we can&amp;rsquo;t stop admiring it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-DSC01399.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from Happo - Nakiyama&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://japan2014.lollback.com/images/2014/12/2014-12-12-DSC01393.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from Happo2 - Nakiyama&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was more snowboarding fun to be had on the journey down. Squeals of joy and giggles were had by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/0SjoRFlm6dg?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked home it started snowing which certainly pleased us.  A great way to finish our wonderful snow experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>